Jesse Firestone | 503-970-2590 | firestonej@gmail.com

Content Management and Interface Developer

With a love of data and a penchant for the perfect user experience, I bridge the gap between front- and back-end development. I have twelve years of programming experience, eight of those years specifically in web development. I'm proficient in Unix and Windows web stacks. I have a wide range of experience as technical lead and developer on projects ranging from home-brewed to million-dollar budgets.

SKILLS:

- Planning and developing large-scale websites, content management systems and applications
- Programming experience with Javascript, PHP, Python, VB.NET/C#, many others
- Responsive front-end experience with Breakpoint/Susy/SASS as well as Bootstrap/LESS
- Frameworks: Drupal, Wordpress, Django, Node/Express, Backbone, visualizations with D3.js
- Automating tasks with tools like Grunt, Docker, drush, etc.
- Strong scoping and discovery skills with an emphasis on planning structure around optimal user experience; experience with technical documentation and proposal writing
- Familiar with developing in a team environment: using source control, working in sprints, building from wireframes, managing and prioritizing effort across many goals

EXPERIENCE:

Co-founder and Lead Developer | Quadruped

September 2014 - Present, Portland, Oregon

- Key part of a focused partnership aimed at building great products for people and organizations that are passionate about what they do
- Created <u>www.setthespread.com</u> responsive web app from concept through beta as product owner and developer
- Front- and back-end development on projects in a variety of frameworks
- Mobile-first responsive development using rapid in-browser prototyping

Developer | Squishymedia

February 2011 - August 2014, Portland, Oregon

- Lead developer on high profile projects including the double Webby award-winning <u>Climate.gov</u>, as well as start2farm.gov, openbooksproject.org, and many others
- Built effective content models and content management systems for large organizations, including many on the Drupal platform
- Took projects from proposal through discovery and deployment on a variety of platforms

Independent Contractor

June 2006 - January 2011, Ashland, Oregon

- Served the needs of clients in Ashland, Medford, Portland, and elsewhere
- Primary focus on business logic or design solutions using a variety of skill sets

EDUCATION:

Southern Oregon University

Studies focused in **Computer Security & Information Assurance** with 90+ credits, including 50+ in Computer-Science related courses.